hello welcome in the first episode of
bug bounty reaper's disgust podcast
this episode is related to the latest
video on my youtube channel bug bounty
reports explained when i described a bug
that allowed stealing private videos
from youtube
it was found by david schutz who is my
guest in this podcast he constantly
finds bugs in google vrp even though
he's only 19 years old from this podcast
you can learn why did he choose to only
hunt on google how he looks for
vulnerabilities what's his advice for
beginners and also what is his
quote-unquote unfair advantage in back
bounty enjoy
hi
thank you for inviting me to this
podcast and thank you for inviting me as
the first guest to this podcast
i am david schutz and
you might know me as ex david who and i
hunt for bugs i do bug bounty and you
might saw my
write-ups on twitter or on
on this youtube channel uh
my latest uh bug was
this uh
youtube tv csrf bag where you could
steal someone's uh private unlisted
videos just by sending them a link so
that's what the last video was was about
and i think it was a very nice video it
explained it very well so great job with
that
thank you i encourage everyone who
didn't see it yet to watch this video on
my youtube channel or maybe read the
write up on david's blog if you prefer
reading david what are you doing besides
back bounty are you studying are you
working what do you do
yeah so
i think that i am 19
years old currently
so uh
that means that i am currently in
university but it's a bit trickier than
that like
i started the
bug bounty around 2018 when i was in uh
like third year i guess of high school
and i was doing bug bounty
uh full time i'm putting like quotes
here full time
with high school but
after high school ended like last year
at the summer
i
transitioned into being a university
student
and
i am currently like studying uh computer
science engineering uh
on uni in university
but uh there is always about i am uh
in the summer of this year i started an
internship at uh at a hungarian um cyber
security education uh
startup application security like secure
coding
startup called avatau
and
i am basically in the last three months
i am i was working at awato and it looks
like i am going to
stay here uh in the future
in the in the future as well um
so i am currently like in
university which is going to like start
in a few days the next year
i am and i am i am doing this internship
uh funnily enough i i have my bug bounty
work has been
i'm not hunting that often uh nowadays
because
i i really like this uh internship and i
really like uh building stuff and and uh
you know uh doing the other side of what
bug bounty is all about like in buck
bounty you try to break stuff and
here i am
i i can finally build stuff so i think
there's a it's important to keep a
balance there i wasn't really able to
find a balance uh currently so in the
last few months i wasn't really hunting
that much
but previously i was back hunting like
full time
if you were a successful buck hunter in
high school
why did you go to university then did
you want to try this this other side or
did you hope that university will help
help you with back bounties
uh
you know i'm not
i i i couldn't give you like a
very great answer for that it's just
like it was like
multiple things uh
first of all this is how
the way
you you go out of high school you go
into university uh here this is like the
normal thing to do you know it's like
casual stuff and so and also there was
like a
little bit of pressure from like uh
from like all sides like parents uh i
don't know like other other people like
it was
it was always there that you should go
to university
and firstly like in high school in the
in the first few years of high school i
was like very against it i didn't want
to go at all like you know i was like i
don't need this like come on like like
this is a waste of time and everything
but uh in the last few years my opinion
kind of like
kind of normalized a little bit or like
isn't so uh
so intense anymore so i i i was like
okay i can
i can try university and see how it goes
and you know see
where to go from there like
it's not really a i really dislike the
idea of uh
judging some somebody based on
a paper that university gives you so i
don't i don't like that at all
but
otherwise um in my first year of
experience kind of shows that uh
and it depends on what classes you take
but i had some negative opinions i had
some positive opinions but
i think my my overall opinion over
one year of going to university is it
like
i'm fine with doing it on the side but i
really don't want to i don't want to
make this my main thing like i don't
want to be
doing university full time like
no
if i can do it on the side uh
while working somewhere where i like to
work or while i'm doing bounty that's
fine but uh
it's not
i don't like it that much to like do it
full time uh so i think that's where i'm
at currently
there are a bit of like messy messy
messy things about that messy emotions
and messy that was like i don't have a
clear answer for that but i am here and
i guess i will see where it goes in the
future
but i'm not really worried about like
you know i have to finish it to get the
paper like
i i don't think uh currently like uh it
would make any difference if i would
have a university degree or if i would
not have a university degree at this
point i don't feel like it would make a
difference
yeah exactly with your resume at the
moment i don't think anyone will will
care about it
do you plan to
continue doing bounties uh after work
and being blue teamer
while at work or you'd like to shift
completely to one of these sides
very great question like these are
questions that i myself can't really
answer like that i think about
on a daily basis uh because
to be honest i was doing bug bounty for
so long and you could laugh at me saying
so long
at 19 and and and
saying that
like three years of doing something is
long but it kind of became like my
identity and i kind of like you know it
it's like really me the bug bounty
person
and
and lately i i really felt like i enjoy
more working in a team working in a
startup environment working and building
trying to build something very nice and
very cool
and um
and i had a little bit of trouble uh
with accepting that that i don't really
want to do bug bounty right now
so
i had to work on that like you know that
like okay like it's fine to not do bug
bounty i'm not going to miss out uh
it's fine if i want to do like
uh
i want to work at the internship now
full time
so
i'm not sure firstly my my idea was like
i should make like you know like try to
balance it like try to do the try to
work and then maybe one day a week do
bug bounty or otherwise or something
like that
but um
but uh
there was no no real system that came
out of this uh in the last three months
so i can't give you a concrete answer
but you know i don't want to give it up
i think it's like you know it's really a
way of thinking or a way of like uh
looking at uh systems like you can't
help but think of how to hack something
it's not like you you just like stop
hacking and stop doing bhagwanti it's
always always there a little bit but i'm
not sure how actively i will do uh like
for example google vrp in the future or
how actively we like how maybe i will
just casually like look at like facebook
or instagram or something like or
youtube like
i can't i can't tell you anything i try
to do what's what's what i feel the best
about
but currently it's hard sometimes to
define
what i what i really want to do that's
yeah
i'm in the middle of that
yeah that's that's a hard question but
one thing for sure whatever you will do
i'm sure when you will find even if you
will be a developer if you find some
dodgy functionality that you are curious
about i'm sure you will
at least spin up developer tools maybe
even burp and and try to find some bug
and with your skills with your finding
you'll probably probably find something
there as well
yeah yeah for i'm not going to let that
let that go and also by the way of
october i'm working currently it's like
really uh
relevant to backbone it's like it's a
platform where
we teach developers how to
like we teach basic like bugs and and
web vulnerabilities and native
vulnerabilities and different types of
vulnerabilities to people
uh
and a bunch of these are like csrf idol
you know all of that that is usually in
the bug bounty space so it's like not
far off
from my bug bounty side so it's a great
great place i think for me to have like
both uh
my bug bounty experience but my regular
relevant security back bounty experience
and my development experience merge
together
yeah
did you first learn to code or did you
learn bounties and you will surprise me
if you tell me you started bounties at
16 and you could code
before
no yeah i i could i could code before
because but not not that long
there was the
we had a few we had a few little
projects uh with a with a friend of mine
like it all started like very very uh
very young we were playing minecraft uh
and we were like doing custom minecraft
servers and all of that stuff you know
and um
and my friend was making plugins for the
minecraft servers and that was very cool
i always wanted to do that always wanted
to write custom plugins but i never i
could i could not learn the program i
could not learn to like write like java
code for the plugins it was very hard
uh so for a few few years i just tried
to get into it but didn't really succeed
but
yeah i think around the start of high
school i started to get a little bit
more into it and um and i made some
little
it started with me making some little
hacking tools on which i put on to
github like
if you look at my github they're like a
bunch of these weird tools like many in
the middle access point point which is
used to like spin up a fake wi-fi
network where you can like with wire
shark monitor traffic and uh
maybe there was like another like lan
ghost where you can like drop a
raspberry pi into a into a network and
if you plug it into the network you can
later control it with a telegram chatbot
so there were these little uh
security projects
after that there was an interesting uh
development which was not security
related uh
with my friend the same the same guy we
made uh
a chatbot for the city that i live in
in hungary sagad the city we we made a
facebook messenger chatbot
that lets people
ask about the
the bus
timetables so you are basically at the
bus stop and you can write a a chat
message on facebook messenger to this
bot and it will respond with the
timetable of the buses so that was a
that got uh like
the media picked that up it was very
nice it was very very fun uh
and we were like both very young like 16
and i was like 15 i think um
so we did that uh
it's still working by the way to this
day
it was very
people are using it but the the funny
thing is that it's very hard to maintain
something for that long like
i i'm learning it on my own on my own
self that uh maintaining legacy code for
like four years is it's not so fun like
it breaks in the middle of like
christmas uh and you have to like debug
it uh at night and like do weird stuff
with it but
but it was a very nice experience i like
to keep it alive and uh
it's a fun it was a fun development
project for for us
uh not related to security and after
that uh in like that was in 2016 and in
2017 2018 is where i
no sorry the messenger chatbot was in
2017 and a year after that i started to
to get into back bounties and i i got
into bug bounties uh because like
i think i think it's really the the
money tweets that got me like as
i'm not sure if this is like good or bad
but i saw it on twitter that
you know the hacker won tweets and the
background tweets at the time or still
that i made uh seven hundred dollars on
background
and i was like like there is no way
that's real like come on guys like like
uh
you know that's not that's not possible
uh i think we all started with seeing
such tweets
yeah they they the tweets really do a
good job and i still saw some people on
twitter who muted those uh
muted those tweets like completely
blocked them
i i could understand that as well but it
was it was motivating you know to get us
all started i think
and
and that that started uh me on the back
bounty path i think
i i started with the point only program
it was under armor uh they had a point
only program on background i reported a
bunch of stuff
i got to the first place of under armour
program because you know it's point only
program no one was really hacking there
and they accepted like duplicate bugs
even
so i i reported the same bug in four
different websites and they all accepted
as as as unique bugs as uh i don't know
it was a bit weird but i got to the top
of the leaderboard that was very nice
uh you know
because it was like underarm or the big
the the
the running like the sport clothing
thing and i saw people on the street
wearing under armour you know clothes
and i was like ha
i i i i hacked that i'm on the
leaderboard
so that was fun and after that i i
started doing a
a paid program i was like you know
it was really really intimidating that i
could not find a bug in a paid program
of course uh but i thought
you know i i could try so i decided that
i will try and uh i will do it for a
week or two weeks or like like as no no
no i decided i will do it until i find a
bug like you know what can i lose really
and a week
or two weeks after starting hacking on a
digital ocean i found a bug there that
was my first ever bug
and i remember i was like really really
freaking out about that when it got the
reward like two or three weeks later i
thought you know they don't care about
it i thought it's like a really bad bug
you know and then i got like five emails
at uh in the evening and it said like a
triage uh rewarded uh unresolved like
all of those emails
and the first bounty was like two
thousand dollars which was which was
insane
uh from digital option program yeah yeah
yeah it was it was the solution right
now they are points only so i think they
they reverted back what was the
vulnerability class
uh it was a
broken
authorization i think that's the very
formal way to say it but it was that
that kind of bug
um that's right that's a great play out
for for high school students
yeah yeah i mean you know it was very
crazy like i i was like calculating that
if i get like the 700 maybe that i saw
on twitter that you know that could that
would cover the the payments of
traveling to c3d the conference the
german security conference that we we
were going to
um that was organized yearly so you know
this was way overly expected like
anything that i expected so that was
that was very crazy uh
to get it as a first bounty
how did you then uh got to google when
did you start hacking on google was it
early in your career or was it rather
lately
so i did i did the
weird to think back i don't even know
what i did i was just like messing
around with random programs like invite
only programs not invite only programs
you know just anything i could see
uh i was i was trying to hack it uh
but
uh
in 2019 at 2019 in in september
i
decided like okay enough of this uh that
i'm moving between all of these
different programs and i don't really
like it it was hard to maintain
motivation to hack on programs that i
know nothing about like you know you get
a private invitation
for a for a like weird application
that's like super complex and you don't
even know how it works and it's like you
don't have any personal connection with
the brand with the tool with the program
so it was hard to to like just like try
to hack that
uh
and it wasn't that successful you know
just like move and try all of the
different programs for me so what i
decided on is like uh in september 2019
that i will focus on google and do just
google
and nothing else
and i did that
i did that because i saw a
saw a guy and i can't i can't remember
the name uh
yeah
but there there is a guy that was there
is a guy who is uh exclusively hacking
on facebook
and i saw that he had like so many bug
reports on facebook and and he
understood so much about facebook i
thought it's really cool and i
and i told that that's the way to go you
know to to go
pick one and go deep
and that's i think it's more rewarding
than to pick try to try to
find the low-hanging fruit on all of the
different programs because most of the
people are like
the the lowing fruit is usually like
taken
so that i choose google vrp
and i started in 2019
september uh and
it's almost
two years
since since that yeah
and how do you choose the the specific
website of google that you will test do
you do a lot of recon
no no no no i
i just
for youtube i chose youtube in the
beginning because that's that was the
product that i was most familiar with
that's the product i use the most i grew
up watching minecraft youtube videos and
i grew up watching all of these
different youtube videos youtube was you
know youtube was my thing like i i know
it i know how it works i knew i knew it
uh so i thought that would be the
coolest you know thing to find a plugin
so that's why i chose youtube in the
first place uh
after that i was looking at different
stuff but it's
yeah with the thing with google is that
they have so many products that all of
those products could be a different bug
bounty program basically so it's like
huge
so you can you can pick and choose
basically uh what i what i usually do
but i don't really i don't think this is
a great process i don't like doing it
it's like feels very unproductive
that's funny thing about bug bounty
everything feels unproductive until you
find a bug like if you are not really
unproductive it just feels like that but
then
at one try it works out and there is a
bug
so it so the whole process was not
unproductive
it's really like a messing with your
brain a little bit
but
um
but uh
yeah i just like go around click around
until i find something interesting
basically that's my recon
a lot of people on twitter ask about the
methodology so
how do you
choose your functionality is it really
you know see and see what seems
appealing to you or is it some kind of
process or methodology which you can say
i think where
i have the most uh success of finding
bugs if i just
try to understand the whole product uh
that's my go-to way that's what i
recommend to anyone who would ask a
question like this it's like to
to really pick one it doesn't matter
which one like everything has bugs in it
like you can pick any any one of it any
any product
pick one product and then go deep try to
understand the whole thing try to
understand the whole product how it
works under the hood better than the
people who wrote it
and that's the key like if you
understand the whole thing better than
the people who made it then you can just
simply think of ways to exploit it and
then you have a bug like i had i had one
uh bug the i'm not sure if you if you
read that i had a write-up about that
when the one abusing the embedded
youtube player to to leak your unlisted
videos
uh i took a look but but didn't read it
read the whole article could you tell us
about it
yeah so it was like you know you have
the embedded youtube player that you can
put into your website if you want to
play videos on your website and
that
youtube player has has an api a
javascript post message api
so your website can control the youtube
player it's very nice it works very well
so your your website can skip for
example a video or load up a playlist
play a video do anything with the comma
send commands to the embedded player
basically
and
the bug was that uh
there was um
there was your unlisted videos playlist
and there was your liked videos playlist
and you know all of these hard-coded
playlist ids
that every user had
and you could load those playlists into
the embedded player it would load the
current visitors playlist and then you
could
send a command to list the videos in the
current playlist to the embedded player
and embed the player would reply like so
basically the attack would look like hey
embedded player
play this
play my uploads playlist
and then the embedded player would start
to play the given users uploads playlist
and then would you ask the embedded
player like hey what videos are in the
current playlist that you are playing
and the embedded player would reply like
yeah here are the ids go ahead
so
it was like you know it's not even a bug
if you think about it it's like kind of
like a feature
but uh
it was a collision that
no no one really thought about using it
this way so there was probably the
embedded player team who were developing
their api
they they post message api and
everything uh
which was working very well and there
was a different team i guess who were
like developing the the the uploads
playlist that everyone has a fixed uh id
uploads playlist uh like the list
playlist you know all these
uh
and and i remember like i was just like
uh looking into this playlist naming
thing on youtube and then looking into
the embedded player thing on youtube and
i wasn't even in front of a computer i
think i i
if i'm remember correctly i was like uh
going to school i was standing on a tram
and i thought like oh yeah like why why
couldn't i just play the uploads
playlist in the embedded player and then
ask later the embedded player like what
video is playing
and and then i got home and tried it and
it worked so it's
it's basically like a feature uh and the
the the reason i'm giving this example
is that i think it really shows off why
understanding the application
as a whole
makes you find bugs easily because it's
not hard to put the two together if you
know about the two things that you have
to put together
and let's say you are testing a
functionality and you've tried
everything you could think of when do
you decide to move on from it
i don't know i don't think i have a
great
answer for it i tend to go
little bit
too deep with that usually i think
um
if i can if i can put can i put a little
personal uh thing in here that i i never
really talked about but
i think it's one of my
one of my real superpowers in in terms
of bug bounty is that
i have
ocd or like obsessive compulsive
disorder if you would call it it's like
99 that i have it i don't have a paper
for it like officially or something but
i really have all of the symptoms of
that and uh
it's a mental thing where i can get very
obsessive about basically anything
and it it's really giving me an unfair
advantage in in terms of back bounty i
think that
uh if there is a functionality or
something that
i i kind of think is like suspicious you
know but but it's not really then even
if i myself i'm like i would be like
lazy like i don't want to like go that
deep like ugh i don't i don't want to do
it i still feel like i must go this deep
and i must look at everything and i must
like i can physically not
keep myself from like obsessing and
going down the rabbit hole sometimes
and the the sad thing about is that it's
it's not a fun experience for me
either but
this
i think there are a bunch of bugs that i
found because of not giving up even
though i wanted to give up but i was
like so obsessive about something that i
could not physically give up
so i was like forcing myself into going
deeper and deeper and deeper and that's
why i find a given bug
uh
so the same thing applies to when do i
stop like i don't know if i get very
like obsessive about something that i
might go way too deep without the need
of going way too deep like
it's a
i
you know
wish i could balance that but like but i
can't really but i just wanted to share
this like
i think it's a very interesting thing i
want to talk more about this because
it's a this ocd thing has a bunch of
other negative aspects and a bunch of
other like stuff unrelated to bug bounty
but
uh here it's it's a weird thing that
it's an unfair it's a superpower and
it's also super bad power
but but the the power of being so you
know feeling like you must you like i
literally feel like i must go this deep
i had uh if i can put like one quick
example here i i remember i was using a
do you know secure the secure notes
application
it's like an encrypted note service kind
of thing and i downloaded it i wanted to
try it out and on my mac uh something
popped up that uh the firewall popped up
saying like
they want to allow connections to this
thing you know and i was like why is it
asking me but i didn't want to check it
i really didn't want to check it i had
way better way many better things to do
but i had this like weird over
responsibility that no no
i must check this one like i have to do
it so i i got like kind of obsessed when
i had to go deep and i i got deep and uh
i i took the thing apart i looked at the
source code it was on github i think it
was open source and i find that it was a
bug that the
the secure note was uh binding
incorrectly binding the web server to
zero zero zero zero zero zero zero yes
so it was binding to every interface
and it was a web server
and the web server had a puff traversal
bug so anyone on your wi-fi network or
on your same network as you could uh
download any file from your computer
using this bug
uh
so
and and it was a secure note application
like an encrypted note-taking app that
was like it was crazy and i reported it
and it got like uh figs like in an hour
that the guy was like very very good
with it but this is just an example that
you know i
if you ask me at that point i don't want
to go d but i feel like i must i feel i
have this over responsibility thing and
i feel like i must go deep
so yeah i just wanted to i just wanted
to add this like this is a weird weird
uh
weird or unfair advantage that i think i
have
yeah i'm sure that that's
an advantage here but probably
not always you're happy that you have it
um yeah could you name maybe a
functionality that you really tried to
hack but but it didn't work at the end
and you spent like days days and trying
to hack this
i don't think i have i don't if there is
no hope at all i don't usually go like
i don't uh spend days if if it's like
nothing there at all i usually spend
days or weeks when there is a bug
already but i want to make it more
impactful
and i have a very hard time stopping in
the middle like i have you know i i find
a bug halfway it's like it's a nice bug
but you know i imagine the the biggest
impact it could have
and i literally can't stop until i
achieve the biggest impact
and i usually that's where i spend most
of my time and sometimes you you it's
just impossible you know you have to
find a different bug to to give the to
make the biggest impact that i want to
make
so that's where i i can give you a
current example but this with what
usually happens that i find something
like moderately serious but then i
imagine in my head like oh this could be
very serious if i could chain it
together with
another thing and i start to look for
the other thing but i can't find the
other thing and you know when do i stop
like
it might be there but it might not be
there like there you have to stop at
some moment the
but when is the right moment to stop the
best question like i i don't have the
answer for that i don't hope i ask i
don't think anyone can answer this
question with a concrete
concrete answer
how do you learn now how do you learn
new things about back bounty
specifically nowadays
uh about back boundaries because i i
think i do a terrible job at learning
about bug bounty currently like
i i don't i don't keep up with the blow
or do the write ups that much anymore i
i well i mean i keep up with the google
stuff like uh i have this github
repository the awesome google vrp
write-ups repository where i
try to aggregate all of the google vrp
write-ups into one place
and i i try to keep up to speed with
that
and there is uh
yeah like
you try to try to understand like and
then and then talk with the other google
hackers um
about what they find
and
i do that but i don't really i don't
really do anything else currently
unfortunately uh
i could do much better if if the
question
is that yeah i could like
you know i'm watching your videos though
i watch the github i watch the github
video uh it was very nice i even i even
started to hack a little bit on github
because of it it was
it was inspiring because i thought you
know maybe i could i could like bypass
the fix there or do something but i
wasn't able to buy post-fix but i
started i i spent a a little uh an
evening trying to trying to mess with
that
yeah i also liked it because it's
especially impressive to me like the way
you
and teddy from from this back hug that
you have one program that you really
know everything about like teddy has a
few nice vulnerabilities on github and
those are functionalities like pull
requests or private videos on youtube
that many of us use on a daily basis
probably equally many tries to hack
those functionalities but only you know
with your previous uh experience you can
do it and for me it's it's especially
impressive this way of of hunting
yeah yeah there was i remember when i
started out like with the bug bounty
stuff i kind of thought you know you i
should never look i wish i
i should find hidden stuff hidden old
functionalities that you know might be
like very bad or very new or something
and i think one take away one important
takeaway
you don't have to like you can just go
straight to the main feature like
why not either go to the
pull request of github try to hang that
like that's the main one of the main
features of like github and go to the
private videos so like this is a very
basic feature of youtube like it's not a
heat done secret new feature that they
just added and it has a has a new bug
that they didn't fix yet no
and don't be afraid of uh
thinking that other people already
looked at it like yeah they looked at it
but they didn't look at the same thing
that you are about to look at yeah
especially know if there are
integrations like
the the google ads also the previous bug
i covered of yours on my channel
um
do you use any tools apart from from
proxy to hunt for bugs
i use yeah i use burp as a proxy that's
i only have the community edition i
don't have the the like the professional
i basically only use the proxy tab and
the repeater tabs like that's it uh
maybe i sometimes use the
the change of user agent you know the
when you can swap around uh the the like
search and replace on the requests i
like i like that it you have to do it
for example for the youtube tv bug you
know you had to swept the user agent uh
i use burp basically and and
i have like i use the android studio uh
a avd emulator basically for android
stuff
and other than that
i might write some custom code if there
is something that i
want to automate
that happened a few times in the last
year that there was a specific
google stuff that i wanted to
you know automate them right tools for
so i made my own tools
uh but other than that uh
but those were not to scan for a
specific vulnerability or or what
yeah like scanning and reconning and
like uh it was basically uh messing with
the the way the google apis work uh
ezekiel uh has uh
he's one of like he's one of the best
google hackers uh
and he he has like talks and and
write-ups about how the how to
explore the google apis and the hidden
fields and methods and all of those the
the different parameters of apis google
has
and he shares a lot of interesting stuff
and i and i tried to make some tools for
myself from from his knowledge to to
apply it more effectively like to scan
or automate this kind of stuff a little
bit but these are mostly like
custom-made tools for very specific
purposes uh
not not
not necessarily for like you know
scanning for a given
specific bug
though it's more like a tool for recon i
would say
and do you use some
scripts or automations that
track changes so they they are supposed
to detect when there is a significant
change in in an application
uh
i did that i did that once but uh i'm i
i'm not doing it anymore but i have a i
can share it that
i had a script it was like very simple
and i don't have it anymore i think but
it was very simple that it uh downloaded
a the google uh
help page like the whole help help page
for a given product like the everything
followed all the sub links and
downloaded every page
and i put it into a github repository
and pushed it to github repository every
every every midnight or something like
that and i had email alerts set up for
the changes on that github repository so
every day i would get an email uh about
uh stuff that's changed in for example
the youtube
help
help documentation like the whole
youtube help documentation so i had some
tooling for that but i stopped doing it
because it it's really hard to to you
know actually find something in that
amount of data like every day
so many things change
uh i even had like some tooling to do to
do the same github the
change tracking trick for the javascript
code of youtube studio one day uh that
was also working nice uh despite the
fact that it like
the cookies like expired every few days
so you had to like relog in and
re-update the cookies to get the
javascript file yeah it was a bit of a
mess so
it's these are great if you do these
properly but it's a lot of work to
maintain them and and to go through all
of the fast positive results it gives
you
did you find any bugs using those
scripts
no no
okay so i know why you don't continue
maintaining them yeah maybe i'm i mean i
guess maybe they they gave me you know a
little bit of information here and there
that i used later on you know but uh no
concrete bugs came out of those
automations and it was a lot of work to
maintain yeah so i kind of stubbed after
y
and for those who are just getting into
the industry
do you think coding skills for example
writing such script do you think it's
necessary to be able to code to get
bounties
no i i don't think it's necessarily it's
kind of like saying uh
i mean maybe it's not the best example
but i don't i really like the fact that
you know you have to know mathematics
to to code like no not really like not
not really currently if you want to go
do
write code that does mathematics then
you have to know mathematics for that
like yeah of course but if you want to
build like a very simple web application
or something then you don't really have
to do any mathematics there i i feel
like the same is true for this like no
you can you can of course find bugs
without knowing how to code
but uh
like
you know knowing how to like how a pro
how computers
do stuff like not even writing code like
not even getting uh
being a python expert or like a
javascript expert or something like that
no just
understanding the basic concept concepts
of how programming languages you know
work and how how
how code works how computers do stuff i
think it's
it's really beneficial i would say maybe
it's necessary yeah
i'm not sure about that uh you know i
came in to back bounty
after
uh you know knowing how to code uh
in like different languages not an
expert in any of that still but
uh you know having a basic idea of how
how
coding logic
is uh
different from like normal everyday
logic
so i had that already uh
i think you have to have some of that
for back bounty i'm not saying you have
to be like
an expert in in
any specific programming language not at
all
if and if you if you learn to properly
program then of course you can make your
own scripts and and tools and stuff like
that that's that's it could be very
useful yeah
yeah i i completely agree on this and
what advice would you give to beginner
bounty hunters
i think similar to what i said earlier
is to go deep
pick some big pick one thing and go deep
and
try to understand the whole product
and don't worry that much about hacking
and the few
in the beginning like
you don't have to hack it you know the
first day or the first week or the first
month no you can just like play around
with all of the different features and
and and learn how it works learn all of
the different like
you can you know get to know it as you
would get to know like a video game you
know that you know every every bit and
piece of how video game works you know
some people can get very into different
games and know everything about it like
i i think the same thing to do with a
specific product
has
massive results so if you for example go
into youtube and then
spend i don't know how much time but
spend a lot of time like just just
trying everything seeing how stuff works
understanding the whole thing and
understanding how it probably works
under the hood
uh
first and after that you can start like
hacking and you don't even have to like
that's what i'm saying that
you know ideas will come to mind if you
understand something that that deep
about how to break it it will be obvious
basically i think
you told before that you started hacking
on vdps i see right now some people are
criticizing vdps and telling that people
shouldn't be hacking on them would you
advise beginners to hack on unpaid
programs
uh i know about this debate yeah that uh
somebody thinks that it's not great
somebody thinks it's fine uh
i don't know like yeah i i see the point
of doing free work for a company is like
a bit unfair
uh you know for me in high school
uh having a bunch of time to to spend on
this uh
i was perfectly fine with it like it was
my choice to do a vdp because i wanted
to do something that's easier than paid
programs and it was my choice to do it i
wasn't you know i wasn't mad or anything
that they didn't pay me and i didn't
feel like oh yeah they are exploiting me
because i'm doing free work i i wasn't
uh i didn't think that i think if you if
you if you're fine with if you're going
to vdp it's because you want to find
something uh if you want to easier
target at first i think that's perfectly
fine that's what i did
uh if you feel like this is a bit of
exploiting and you don't want to do it
but you feel like you must do it to get
private invites no i don't think
uh you must do it like if you don't want
to then then just go with the paid
programs
i don't really hack on private programs
anyway so i i don't really have a
motivation to like collect points for
invites you know
yeah yeah i understand and a question
not really connected to back bounties
but you are on twitter but you have
zero you are following nobody what's the
story behind it
uh
yeah i
the story behind
that is
it's not like because i'm trying it's
not because i'm trying to be cool uh or
something it has it has it's cool
let's admit it it's it's it's cool to
have followers and have uh follow zero
people that that wasn't the goal uh
and it's not the goal currently it
i a while ago i was like just like i'm
always in an in and out about
uh using social media and you know i i
use it a lot and then i decide to quit
social media and then i go back to
social media and do that
every year every month like
it's a little bit of a back and forth
always and i had this that i was like
doing spending on much time on twitter
and i didn't want to like uninstall
twitter because i have the interactions
there i have someone mentions me if i if
i you know i want to post something
there uh i want to have twitter there
but i didn't want to scroll the feed so
that's when i
decided that i made my feed empty
so i unfollowed everyone so now that my
my feed is empty and i i have a list i
have a on twitter you can make lists so
i have a list of like a few people where
there it makes like a separate feed for
those few people
i don't know like um
i don't think this is i'm not sure about
this decision i i just like unfollowed
everyone once because there was like too
much
too much thing in my feed and i was like
scrolling too many too much twitter
and i turned my twitter account into
like a you know where i post my work and
i don't really do anything there uh
besides that but but i do have it to
check if you send me a message or if
someone you know reaches out or
something like that of course i
i check it once in a while but i'm not
using that activity that's the reason
behind it but
this is really really not a real uh
not a real argument against it like i
could follow a bunch of people as well
it's just like eh i unfollowed
everyone like
last year i think for this reason yeah
that's it
yeah i'm going back and forth with
removing and bringing back mobile
applications of twitter of youtube or of
different applications which i'm not
sure if i need them because sometimes i
i find myself checking for the
notifications just too often
but yeah i also believe that with uh
with bounties with internship and with
university you you don't have much time
because i've been in a similar position
so so i suppose you well you really need
to be quick
i'm not sure yeah i wouldn't say that i
if you i have an embarrassing thing i
one weekend no one sunday it was one day
i spent seven hours on tick tock seven
so it was almost like a full birthday
and it was terrible like after that i
opened youtube and i was like god then i
i have to choose the video to watch like
how lame is that like this is a boomer
thing so uh
i
tic talk is crazy um but in the funny
that you say that yeah i'm always going
back and forth between that
as well like i uninstall the youtube app
because i don't want to watch youtube
but then i end up using the web
interface and that sucks because i can't
you know it like messes up every every
single time and then i download the
youtube app and for a few months i was
like oh yeah i'm not really looking at
youtube but then i start looking at
youtube again right like it's a cycle
yeah
yeah for me
at the moment for example i have
i don't have facebook but
also i'm logged in in safari and when
something happens when i expect some
notifications i just see that in safari
and it doesn't make sense but
the the screen time restriction is
helping helping a bit with that
okay i have a last question for you
name one thing it might be a script an
automation a habit or a purchase
whatever that saved you a lot of time
lately that's made you more productive
in back bounties or yeah i guess it
doesn't have to be
uh
okay i have one it's
like i'm answering questions uh in an
outside of the box way like i don't i
never gave a kind of a concrete answer
to any question you asked me before
i have something similar here as well
i think a productive tip is to not worry
about your equipment like i
what i learned in the last couple of
years i spent so much time worrying
about oh yeah i buy this computer but i
buy this monitor but inside that the
monitor is like has better refresh rate
that has better pixels this phone has a
better battery and you know after i buy
all of these different things i end up
like thinking like oh yeah it really
doesn't matter at all like
like
yeah i have a it's it's you know it's
not the fastest computer it's not the
slowest like
after you buy it it doesn't matter so
it's like just just just do what you
want to do and don't don't uh try to
like uh make the equipment perfect
you can't really doesn't matter at all
that's my advice
also of topic regarding this i'm playing
rocket league sometimes and in rocket
league sometimes people in their logins
that's the login visible in the
scoreboard for example they put for
example greg on 144 hertz that's the
refresh rate of the monitor like it
would change their skill significantly
that's ridiculous weird flags weird play
okay
that's fine
wow
thank you david for coming to the
podcast i really enjoyed this talk and
i'm sure that viewers also did and have
many takeaways that they can take from
this talk
thank you thank you for having me again
i i hope i
i could give you something valuable and
it was a it was very nice to to talk to
you
[Music]
thank you a lot for listening to this
podcast
if you enjoyed it subscribe to never
miss a new episode you can do it on
youtube but also in your favorite
podcasting app like apple podcasts or
spotify
this will also help this episode reach
other people who might find it
interesting
thank you in advance and goodbye
[Music]